Guide to the Stanford University, Office of Vice President and General Counsel, Records SC0178
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of Vice President and General Counsel, records
1968-1976
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Office of the General Counsel
SC0178
13.5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
These records are office files maintained by Siena's office during his term as Legal Advisor to the President. Primary concerns were faculty and student affairs, campus security and demonstrations, personnel, university and government relations. The files include correspondence, memoranda, notes and supporting documents.
Separated Materials
The following materials were removed from the collection.
Federal regulations and xeroxes of pages from the federal register unless specifically part of a letter or other communication.
Published pamphlets regarding the by-laws, charters, etc., of boards of trustees or overseers of major U.S. colleges and universities.
Duplicates of Stanford related published documents.
Arrangement
The material is arranged in eleven series: 1. Campus disruptions, 2. Campus security, 3. Faculty affairs, 4. Government relations, 5. Personnel, 6. Lands and buildings, 7. Schools and departments, 8. Student affairs, 9. University relations, 10. Miscellaneous, 11. Additional material.
Box Listing
Box Series 1 Campus Disruptions 2 Campus Security 3 Faculty Affairs 4 Government Relations 5 Personnel 6 Lands and Buildings (A to F) 7 (d.b.) Lands and Buildings (G to Z) Schools and Departments 8 Student Affairs 9 Student Affairs University Relations 10 Miscellaneous 11-21 Additional material
All boxes are record storage cartons except #7, a document box.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfer, President's Office, 1977.
Information about Access
Restricted: written permission required from President's Office until documents are 25 years old. For more information, contact the University Archivist.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
A Stanford law graduate (1961), Siena was appointed legal advisor to the President of the University in January 1970. Formerly associated with Covington & Burling, a prominent Washington D. C. law firm, Siena later served in the Department of the Army as Deputy Under Secretary for International Affairs. He also served as a consultant to the Office of Economic Opportunity and a member of the Board of the National Capital Area Civil Liberties Union.
As Legal Advisor to the President, Siena worked with Presidents Kenneth Pitzer (January 1970 to September 1970) and Richard Lyman (September 1970 to 1977) as well as the provost and other university officials on legal matters. He acted as liaison with outside counsel, reviewed campus operations in light of existing laws and regulations, and monitored legislative and regulatory changes affecting the University.
Description of the Collection
These records are office files maintained by Siena's office during his term as Legal Advisor to the President. Primary concerns were faculty and student affairs, campus security and demonstrations, personnel, university and government relations. The files include correspondence, memoranda, notes and supporting documents.
Related Materials
President's Office Records, 1970-1977 (restricted)
University Relations, SC
Peter Allen: Student Demonstrations papers, SC 157
Siena, James V: Stanford news release, 12-5-69
Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Stanford University. Office of the General Counsel; Siena, James V.; Stanford University. Office of the General Counsel
- Campus disruptions, Series 1
  - Stanford (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - General (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Campus Disruptions, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Campus Disruptions (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Campus Disruptions #2 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - April 3rd Movement, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Scope and Contents
    Miscellaneous documents.
  - Rock Throwing & Campus Unrest, 1972 Apr 17-21 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1971 Apr (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Assault on Benjamin & Jeppson (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Calloway, Auburn - Vienna Campus, 1971 May (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - CP & Placement Center Incident, 1971 Apr 19 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Career Planning & Placement Center, 1972 Nov 1, 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - CP & Placement Center, 1972 Jan 26 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Computation Center, 1971 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Computation Center Occupation, 1971 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Cost of Disruption, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Campus Disruptions - Cost (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Campus Security (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - FCM Beating, 1971 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Hospital Disruption: Dolly Grievance Hearing (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Hospital Sit-In, 1971 Spring (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Hoover Conference on Iran, 1971 Oct 18, 19 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Injunction & Related Matters (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Lodge Speech at Dinkelspiel, Disruption of, 1971 Jan 11 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Lodge Disruption - Keilch Case (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Marine Recruiting - PC, 1973 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - McClellan Committee (US Senate), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Mecha Incident, 1971 Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Meyer Library Incident, 1973 Oct 4 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Physics & Durand Trashing, 1970 Nov 23 (Item 1, Folder 52)
  - President's Commission, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Psy/Comm 80, Communication & Beh, An Expt, 1971 Oct (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Rally on White Plaza, 1973 Jan 4 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - SCCSD Camera - Arrest of M. Weiss (Item 1, Folder 56)
  - Anti-ROTC Disruptions, 1970 Spring (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Professor William Shockley's class, 1972 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - White, Ray - Incident outside Memorial Church (Item 1, Folder 59)
  - U Wisconsin (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yale (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Non-Stanford
    - Commission on Campus Disorders (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Campus Disruptions - Other Campuses (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alabama University (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - U of Calif (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - UC Riverside (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - UCSB (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - U Chicago (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Harvard (Bin 1, Folder 8)
    - U of Illinois (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - U of Iowa (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - U of NM (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - NYU (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - NYC U (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - UNC (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Northwestern (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Princeton (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - U of Rochester (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - SF State (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - San Jose State (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - U Washington (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Campus security, Series 2
  - Attorney General's Opinions (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bomb Threats (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Campus Police, Needed Changes Re (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Campus Police - Statistics (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Campus Police - Stolen Goods (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Civil Code Re Lost & Found (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Complaints and/or Referrals, 1971 Sep-1972 Aug (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Complaints and/or Referrals, 1972 Sep-1973 Sep (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Complaints and/or Referrals, 1973 Sep (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Computer Security (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Death of David Levine (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Director of Police Services at Stanford, Chief Herrington (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dogs on Campus (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Handwriting Analysts (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum of Understanding - Sheriff's Office (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Peace Officer Legislation (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Peace Officer Standards and Training (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Police Reports, 1970 Oct-1971 Aug (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Police Reports, 1971 Sep-1972 Aug (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Police Reports, 1972 Sep-1973 Aug (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Police Reports, 1973 Sep (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Policy on Photographs (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Power Systems Security (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Presidential Commission on the Status of the Stanford Police (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Reorganization of SDPS under MLH (Item 2, Folder 25)
  - Rock Concerts (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Security - General (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Security at Football Games (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Security Procedures (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Security Devices, General (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Security Device: Mark Systems, Inc (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Security Device: Night Owl (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Security Device: Singer Libra Scope (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Security Re RWL (Bldg 10) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Security: SLAC (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Stanford Alpine Club - Practice Climbing on Campus (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - SDPS Manual of Rules, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Vehicle Permits (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Weapon Legislation (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Faculty affairs, Series 3
  - Advisory Board Rules (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Am Assn of Univ Profs (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Prof Begle (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cancian, Franzi (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Committee on the Professoriate (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Contract (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Affairs - General (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Faculty and Academic Freedom (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Grievance Procedure (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Self Discipline (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Self Discipline (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Visas (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Jean Franco/Visa (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Kreisel-Friedman Case (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Kreisel-Friedman Case (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pound-Chace Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pound-Chace Materials (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - William Shockley (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Professor Solomon (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Robert Textor (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Government relations, Series 4
  - Academic Senate (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - BAP and Tenure (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees - Committee on Investment Responsibility (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees - Delegation of Powers (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees - Delegation (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Budget & Finance (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - CDC v. IBM (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - GM Campaign (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - GM Project #2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - GM Project (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - GM Project (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Human Relations Commission (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ombudsman (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Public Events - General (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - ROTC #2, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - ROTC, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - SJC (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - SJC #3 (See Also CJP), 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - SCLC (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Trustees' ByLaws (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - University Legal Services (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - University Legal Services (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Personnel, Series 5
  - ABA Committee on Alcohol & Drug Ref (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Affirmative Action, 1969-1971 May (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action, 1971 Dec-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Affirmative Action - Officer Candidates (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Affirmative Action - Reports & Docs (External) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Affirmative Action - External (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Benefits (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bonding Employees (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - CAL FEPC (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Career Planning & Placement Center (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Child Care Center (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Credit Union (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Equal Employment Opportunities (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dept of Labor MDTA Problem (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - General, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - General, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Grievance Arbitrations (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Grievance Decisions (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Grievance Procedures, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Insurance (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Labor Relations (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Non Reappointment of Extradepartmental Personnel (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Occupational Health and Safety (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Remson Case (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Student Employment & Guidelines (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Tunney Campaign (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Union Elections (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - USE Negotiations, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Lands and buildings, Series 6
  - Annexation (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Campus Parking (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Coyote Hills (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Lands and Buildings, General, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Faculty/Staff Housing Council (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Frenchman's Terrace (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Land Use Policy (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lands & Buildings - General, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lands & Buildings - General (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lyman Lease (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Low-Income Housing #2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Low-Income Housing - Board Actions (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Church (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Church (other Religions) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Physical Education and Athletics Facilities (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Pub & Liquor Policy (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - '74 Shrine Game, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Use of Facilities by Outsiders (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Schools and departments, Series 7
  - Business Schools (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Foreign Study Programs (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Computer Facilities (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Daily (Political-Legislative Editorials) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Daily Search (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Earth Sciences Proposal (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - ERG - Electron Radiography (Henry Kaplan) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - General File (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Graduate Studies (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Hoover Institution (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Hospital Search (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Johnson Foundation (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Law School (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Medical School Admissions (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Medical School Clinics Problems (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - School of Medicine (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Overseas Campuses (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Overseas Campus - CIEE Ticket Problem (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Overseas Campus - Britain (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Overseas Campus - France/Germany/Austria (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Overseas Campus - Italy (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - PEP (Proton-Electron Positron) Agreement (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Phys Ed and Athletics (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - SLAC & Facility Installations (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Stanford University Hospital (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Tennis Proposal (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Tresidder Union (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Undergraduate Studies (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - University Libraries (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Student affairs, Series 8
  - Student Affairs - General (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Political Activity (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Power, Conflict, and ROTC: Foote/Durham (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - KZSU St. 3.18 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Residences & Housing (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Delta Tau Delta (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Fraternity Agreements (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - GI Bill matters (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Health Service (Cowell) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Students on Committees (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Minority - General (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Student Legal Services (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Drug Abuse Program (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Admissions & Registrar's Office: Corresp. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Financial Aid & Bankruptcy & Loans (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Voluntary Organizations (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - ASSU Finances - Fundraising & Fee Assessments (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - ASSU Constitution (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - ROTC (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Daily (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Chaparral (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Daily Independence Study (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Daily Independence Documents (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Daily (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Admission of Women (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Admissions & Financial Aids (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - ARLO (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Contraceptives (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Health Service - Contraceptives (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Gay Students (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - KZSU (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Minority Student Relations (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Pre-Paid Legal Services (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Political Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Political Activities Recess (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Sweeny (Box 9, Folder 28)
- University relations, Series 9
  - Alumni Relations (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Need (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Complaint Letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Robert Louis Fincher (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Fund Raising, General (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - General (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Goldman, Sachs, & Co (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hopkins Deed Restriction (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - IBM Agreements (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Labor Relations - Hospital (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - New Founders League (Fund Raise) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Student Aid (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Palo Alto/Univ Relations (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Police Dept Agreement (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Police Protection (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - USE Negotiations (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous, Series 10
  - Attorney Applications (Item 10, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Board Grievance Rules (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Committee of Fifteen, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Committee of Fifteen, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Committee of Fifteen, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Committee of Fifteen, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Guidelines (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - ISI Sign off Procedures (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - RWL's Committee on Privacy (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Privacy Committee (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Termination - Graduate Study (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Title IX (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Title IX (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Additional material, 1963-1977; Series 11
  - Affirmative action, 1966-1977; Subseries 1
    - Affirmative Action & Equal Pay, AAU Committee on, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Affirmative Action & Equal Pay, AAU Committee on. Folder #1, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Affirmative Action & Equal Pay, AAU Committee on. Folder #2, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Affirmative Action & Equal Pay, AAU Committee on - Washington D.C., 1975 Jan 31 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - H.E.W. Guidelines on Affirmative Action, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Law School - Mark R. Forcum, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Minority Financial Aids, 1974-1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Minority Housing Proposals, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Title VI - HEW - Medical School & Law School, 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Title VII and Faculty, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Title IX - General, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Title IX - General. Folder #1, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Title IX - General. Folder #2, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Title IX - Fraternities, general, 1956-1974 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Title IX - Fraternities, corresp., 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Title IX - Fraternities, internal documents & reports. Folder #1, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Title IX - Fraternities, internal documents & reports. Folder #2, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Title IX - Fraternities, letters of commendation/complaint, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Title IX - Fraternities, Daily articles, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Title IX - NCAA, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Title IX - NCAA. Folder #1, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Title IX - NCAA. Folder #2, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Title IX - NCAA, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Applied Data Research, Inc., 1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Arms Control Seminar, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Brown Act, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Budget, Academic. Folder #1, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Budget, Academic. Folder #2, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Budget, Academic. Folder #1, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Budget, Academic. Folder #2, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Budget, Academic. Folder #3, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - CEFA Bond Offering, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Committee of 15, 1972 May (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Incl. Minutes.
    - Committee of 15, 1972 May-1973 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Committee of 15, 1971 Feb-1972 Apr (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Committee on Public Events (COPE), 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Incl. Minutes.Incl. Minutes)Incl. Minutes)
    - Committee on Public Events (COPE), 1975-1976 (Item 12, Folder 14)
    - Cooney, Joseph, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Demonstrations, Stanford - News Releases, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Demonstrations - Lodge Incident - Drafts of Statements on Charges, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Demonstrations - White Plaza, Computation Center, Drafts of Statements on Charges, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dean of Students, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Electron Micro Research, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Faculty/staff affairs, 1970-1976; Subseries 2
    - Academic Employment Relationship (AER). Folder #1, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 21Academic Employment Relationship (AER))
    - Academic Employment Relationship (AER). Folder #2, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - AAUP Report - Current Faculty Grievance Procedures, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Anderson, John, 1976 Mar (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Becker, Eugene, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Butler-Paisley, Matilda, Complaint, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "Consulting Policies at Six Universities", Report, 1976 Apr 26 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Faculty Observers, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Harries - Visa, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Mandell - Visa, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Mason, Anne, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - McNulty, Carol, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Miller, Myrna, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Rauch, Helene, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Governance/administration, 1966-1975; Subseries 3
    - Anti-Trust Law, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Dean's Council, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Electric Power Research Institute, Inc., 1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Fundamental Standard & Honor Code, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Hoover Legislation, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Judicial System, 1971-1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Police & Campus Security, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Police & Campus Security, 1972-1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Police Commission, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Police Dept. at UCB, 1967-1970 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Police District. Folder #1, 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Police District. Folder #2, 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Police Legislation, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Research, 1970-1975 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Tax Law, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Tax Law, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Trespass Law, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - University Address Lists, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Government relations, 1967-1976; Subseries 4
    - California Educational Facilities Authority, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - California Legislation, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Copyright - General, 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Copyrights - New, 1972-1975 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Economic Stabilization Program (Price Freeze), 1973 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Folder #1, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Folder #2, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Folder #3, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Federal Legislation. Folder #1, 1969-1973 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Federal Legislation. Folder #2, 1969-1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Federal Legislation - State/Justice/Commerce Rider, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Government Policy Group. Folder #1, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Inc. Minutes.
    - Government Policy Group. Folder #2, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Government Policy Group. Folder #3, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Government Policy Group, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Hebert Amendment, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Lobbying Act, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - McClellan Committee Subpoena. Folder #1, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - McClellan Committee Subpoena. Folder #2, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)